Guide to the C. Vann Woodward Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1927-2000; Series I
  - Civil Liberties Review, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Clancy, John J., Jr., 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Claremont Graduate School, 1957-1980 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Clark, Thomas D., 1941-1957, 1982, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - Claus, Ruth, 1978-1982, undated (Box 12, Folder 128)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 16
  - Clinton, William Jefferson and Hillary Rodham, 1993-1994, undated (Box 12, Folder 129)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 555
  - Cochran, Thomas C., 1948-1972 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - Coles, Robert, 1966-1997 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - Colgate University, 1961-1989 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - College of William and Mary, 1941-1978 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Columbia University [includes general correspondence, the Forum, Columbia University Press, and Teacher's College], 1947-1982 (Box 12, Folder 134 - 135)
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 1939, 1950, 1967-1972, undated (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Commentary, 1956-1976 (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1951-1972 (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Connecticut College, 1952-1985 (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Contee, Clarence, 1956-1961 (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Cornell University [includes general correspondence and Cornell University Press], 1957-1978 (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Couch, William T., 1938-1969 (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Coulter, E. Merton, 1939, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Craven, Avery, 1940-1969, undated (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Crofts, Daniel, 1970-1997 (Box 13, Folder 145)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 17
  - Crowell, Thomas Y., Company, 1958-1967 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, 1955-1989 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Cunningham, Raymon J., 1958-1966 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Current History, 1956-1969 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Curry, Richard O., 1964-1974 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Curti, Merle, 1947-1970, undated (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Curtin, Philip D., 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - D [general], 1939-1999, undated (Box 14, Folder 153 - 158)
  - Dabbs, James McBride, 1960-1967 (Box 14, Folder 159)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 610
  - Dabney, Virginius, 1940-1967 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Daedalus, 1965-1999 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1959-1969 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Daniels, Jonathan, 1957-1958; 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Dartmouth College, 1958-1991 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Dauer, Manning, 1938-1982, undated (Box 15, Folder 165 - 167)
  - Davis, David Brion, 1964-1994, undated (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Degler, Carl N., 1960-1995 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - DeSantis, Vincent, 1949-1978, undated (Box 15, Folder 170 - 171)
  - Dew, Charles B., 1961-1998 (Box 16, Folder 172 - 173)
  - Dickinson College, 1953-1969 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - Donald, David, 1951-1984 (Box 16, Folder 175 - 176)
  - Doubleday and Co., 1954-1983 (Box 16, Folder 177)
  - Douglass, Frederick, Papers of, 1971-1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 178)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 79
  - Duberman, Martin, 1962-1974 (Box 16, Folder 179)
  - Du Bois, W. E. B., 1938, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 180)
  - Duke University [includes general correspondence, Center for Southern Studies, and Duke University Press], 1952-1983 (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - Durden, Robert F., 1950-1982, undated (Box 16, Folder 182)
  - Durr, Clifford and Virginia, 1940-1984, undated (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - E [general], 1947-1997, undated (Box 17, Folder 184 - 185)
  - Earl, Charles H., 1938-1964 (Box 17, Folder 186)
  - Eaton, Clement, 1952-1969, undated (Box 17, Folder 187)
  - Edelstein, Tilden, 1954-1971, undated (Box 17, Folder 188 - 189)
  - Educational Broadcasting Corp., 1962-1977 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1943, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - Elkins, Stanley, 1958-1996 (Box 17, Folder 192)
    See also: Series III. Subjects, 1947-1997 Folder 10
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 487 - 494
  - Ellis, Joseph J., 1977, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 193)
  - Ellison, Ralph, 1968-1982 (Box 17, Folder 194)
  - Emory University [includes general correspondence, the library, and Emory University Quarterly ], 1940-1989 (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959-1970 (Box 17, Folder 196)
    Includes general correspondence and Encyclopedia Britannica Films.
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1957-1994 (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - Engerman, Stanley L., 1968-1982, undated (Box 17, Folder 198)
  - England, Martha (cousin?), 1958-1962, undated (Box 17, Folder 199)
  - Engs, Robert F., 1966-1992 (Box 17, Folder 200)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 18
  - F (general), 1938-1997 (Box 18, Folder 201 - 204)
  - Faulkner, William [copies of letters between Faulkner and Rev. Jones, from Robert Elijah Jones Papers], 1940 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Faust, Drew Gilpin, 1975-1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation [Woodward's request for his file], 1997 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Ferguson, Charles W., 1938-1970 (Box 18, Folder 208)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 545
  - Fields, Barbara, 1974-1994 (Box 18, Folder 209)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 19
  - Fischer, David Hackett, 1958-1970 (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - Fischer, Mary Lu (cousin), 1951-1970 (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - Fischer, Roger A., 1968-1971 (Box 18, Folder 212)
  - Fishel, Leslie H., Jr., 1948-1965 (Box 18, Folder 213)
  - Fisk University, 1956-1970 (Box 18, Folder 214)
  - Fleet, Betsy, 1964-1978, undated (Box 18, Folder 215)
  - Fogel, Robert W., 1965-1998 (Box 18, Folder 216)
  - Foner, Eric, 1963-1990 (Box 18, Folder 217)
  - Foner, Philip S., 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 218)
  - Ford Foundation, 1957-1978, undated (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Fowler, Wilton B., 1963-1977 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Fox-Genovese, Elizabeth, 1972-1982 (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Franklin, John Hope [see also City University of New York: Brooklyn College], 1948-1997 (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Frazier, E. Franklin, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 223)
  - Frederickson, George M., 1968-1985 (Box 19, Folder 224)
  - Freehling, William W., 1971-1982 (Box 19, Folder 225)
  - Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1948-1952 (Box 19, Folder 226)
  - Freidel, Frank, 1952-1984 (Box 19, Folder 227)
  - Fuchs, Lawrence H., 1957-1960 (Box 19, Folder 228)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1951-1956, undated (Box 19, Folder 229)
  - G (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 20, Folder 230 - 234)
  - Garraty, John A., 1955-1985 (Box 20, Folder 235)
  - Gaston, Paul, 1965-1999, undated (Box 20, Folder 236)
  - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., 1979 (Box 21, Folder 237)
  - Gatzke, Hans, 1947-1982, undated (Box 21, Folder 238)
  - Gay, Peter and Ruth, 1960-1993, undated (Box 21, Folder 239)
  - Genovese, Eugene D., 1957-1998, undated (Box 21, Folder 240 - 241)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology, 1956-1968 (Box 21, Folder 242)
  - Gettleman, Marvin E., 1959-1976 (Box 21, Folder 243)
  - Gettysburg College, 1957-1981 (Box 21, Folder 244)
  - Gilchrist, David, 1960-1966 (Box 21, Folder 245)
  - Giliomee, Hermann, 1973-1998 (Box 21, Folder 246)
  - Gillette, J. William, 1965-1974 (Box 21, Folder 247)
  - Gingrich, Newt, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 248)
  - Goldman, Eric, 1947-1970, undated (Box 21, Folder 249)
  - Goodman, James, 1994-1998 (Box 21, Folder 250)
  - Goodwyn, Lawrence, 1967-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 251)
  - Gottschalk, Louis, 1956-1970 (Box 21, Folder 252)
  - Govan, Thomas, 1948-1961 (Box 21, Folder 253)
  - Graff, Henry F., 1962-1972 (Box 21, Folder 254)
  - Graham, Edward K., 1968-1973 (Box 21, Folder 255)
  - Graham, Howard J., 1954-1967 (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - Grantham, Dewey W., 1955-1978 (Box 22, Folder 257)
  - Green, Fletcher M., 1948-1960 (Box 22, Folder 258)
  - Green, James, 1967-1996, undated (Box 22, Folder 259)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 21
  - Green, Paul, 1958-1960 (Box 22, Folder 260)
  - Greenfield, Kent Roberts, 1947-1961, undated (Box 22, Folder 261)
  - Greensboro Daily News, 1962-1975 (Box 22, Folder 262)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1949-1979, undated (Box 22, Folder 263)
  - Gutman, Herbert G., 1964-1974, undated (Box 22, Folder 264)
  - H (general), 1938-1997, undated (Box 23, Folder 265 - 271)
  - Hackney, Lucy and Sheldon, 1963-1997, undated (Box 24, Folder 272)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 22
  - Hahn, Steve, 1980-1998, undated (Box 24, Folder 273)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 23
  - Hall, Robert F., 1938, 1986, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 274)
  - Hamlett, Ed, 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 275)
  - Handlin, Oscar, 1951-1968 (Box 24, Folder 276)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and Co., 1950-1995, undated (Box 24, Folder 277 - 279)
  - Harlan, Louis R., 1948-1996, undated (Box 25, Folder 280)
  - Harper and Brothers / Harper and Row, Publishers, 1952-1975 (Box 25, Folder 281 - 282)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1937-1976, undated (Box 25, Folder 283)
  - Harvard Educational Review, 1959-1975 (Box 25, Folder 284)
  - Harvard University
    - General, 1941-1997 (Box 25, Folder 285)
    - Charles Warren Center, 1967-1981 (Box 25, Folder 286)
  - Harvard University Press
    - General, 1949-1992, undated (Box 25, Folder 287)
    - John Harvard Library, 1959-1971, undated (Box 25, Folder 288)
  - Hassler, Warren W., 1951-1998 (Box 25, Folder 289)
  - Hawgood, John A., 1954-1957, undated (Box 25, Folder 290)
  - Hawkins, Hugh, 1954-1976, undated (Box 26, Folder 291)
  - Hayes (Rutherford B.) Memorial Library, 1949-1956, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 292)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 293)
  - Heinrichs, Waldo, 1961-1967 (Box 26, Folder 294)
  - Hersey, Barbara and John, 1974-1992, undated (Box 26, Folder 295)
  - Hewes, James A., Jr., 1961-1970 (Box 26, Folder 296)
  - Hexter, Jack, 1963-1993, undated (Box 26, Folder 297)
  - Higham, John, 1956-1996 (Box 26, Folder 298)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1959-1960 (Box 26, Folder 299)
  - History and Theory, 1960-1998 (Box 26, Folder 300)
  - Hofstadter, Beatrice (Mrs. Richard Hofstadter), 1963-1977, undated (Box 26, Folder 301)
  - Hofstadter, Richard, 1950-1970, undated (Box 26, Folder 302)
  - Holt, Thomas, 1972-1994, undated (Box 26, Folder 303)
  - Holt and Co., Inc., Publishers / Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, Inc., 1951-1965 (Box 26, Folder 304)
  - Homma, Nagayo, 1953-1964 (Box 26, Folder 305)
  - Hoogenboom, Ari, 1956-1973 (Box 26, Folder 306)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1955-1979 (Box 26, Folder 307)
  - Howard University, 1948-1975 (Box 26, Folder 308)
  - Huie, C. R. [Arkansas boyhood friend], 1938-1982, undated (Box 26, Folder 309)
  - Huntington Library, 1960-1982 (Box 27, Folder 310)
  - Hyman, Harold M., 1964-1966 (Box 27, Folder 311)
  - I (general), 1938-1984 (Box 27, Folder 312 - 313)
  - Indiana University [includes general correspondence and Indiana University Press], 1958-1974 (Box 27, Folder 314)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, 1956-1975 (Box 27, Folder 315)
  - Institute of Contemporary History, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 316)
  - International Council on the University Emergency, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 317)
  - J (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 27, Folder 318 - 320)
  - Jenkins, Ray, 1963-1995 (Box 27, Folder 321)
  - Jensen, Richard, 1966-1970 (Box 27, Folder 322)
  - Johnson, Gerald W., 1938-1969 (Box 27, Folder 323)
  - Johnson, Ludwell, 1955-1982, undated (Box 28, Folder 324)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1957-1966, undated (Box 28, Folder 325)
  - Johnson, Walter, 1949-1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 326)
  - Johns Hopkins Club, 1947-1963 (Box 28, Folder 327)
  - Johns Hopkins University
    - General, 1947-1990, undated (Box 28, Folder 328 - 330)
    - Library, 1949-1959, undated (Box 28, Folder 331)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1947-1993 (Box 28, Folder 332)
  - Jones, William T., 1953-1992 (Box 28, Folder 333)
  - Jordan, Winthrop D., 1966-1973 (Box 28, Folder 334)
  - Josephson, Matthew, 1938-1940, 1966-1970 (Box 28, Folder 335)
  - Journal of American History (formerly Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1964-1975 (Box 28, Folder 336)
  - Journal of American Studies, 1966-1980 (Box 29, Folder 337)
  - Journal of Negro Education, 1956-1959 (Box 29, Folder 338)
  - Journal of Southern History, 1937-1997, undated (Box 29, Folder 339)
  - Joyner, Charles, 1987-1997 (Box 29, Folder 340)
  - K (general), 1937-1997, undated (Box 29, Folder 341 - 345)
  - Kagan, Donald, 1982-1996, undated (Box 29, Folder 346)
  - Kaji, Shinzo, 1954-1965 (Box 29, Folder 347)
  - Karlin, Jules Alexander, 1939-1969 (Box 30, Folder 348)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1993, undated (Box 30, Folder 349)
  - Kelley, Sally [Arkansas friend], 1964-1982 (Box 30, Folder 350)
  - Kellogg, Charles Flint and Mary-Margaret, 1948-1969 (Box 30, Folder 351)
  - Kelly, Alfred H., 1955-1974 (Box 30, Folder 352)
  - Kennan, George, 1953-1957 (Box 30, Folder 353)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1957 (Box 30, Folder 354)
  - Kennedy, Randall, 1973-1975 (Box 30, Folder 355)
  - Key, Jack, 1958-1966 (Box 30, Folder 356)
  - Key, Valdimer Orlando (V. O.), Jr., 1948 (Box 30, Folder 357)
  - Kilpatrick, Carroll, 1938-1979, undated (Box 30, Folder 358)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 706
  - Kilson, Martin, 1971-1976 (Box 30, Folder 359)
  - King, Martin L., Jr., 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 360)
  - Kirwan, A. D., 1948-1969 (Box 30, Folder 361)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., Inc., 1948-1996, undated (Box 30, Folder 362 - 364)
  - Kolko, Gabriel, 1967-1982 (Box 30, Folder 365)
  - Kousser, J. Morgan, 1969-1999 (Box 31, Folder 366)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 26
  - Kraditor, Aileen [mostly regarding Herbert Aptheker], 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 367)
  - L (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 31, Folder 368 - 372)
  - Lamar, Howard, 1962-1987, undated (Box 31, Folder 373)
  - Lane, Frederick C., 1954-1969 (Box 31, Folder 374)
  - Lane, Mills Bee, IV, 1965-1977 (Box 31, Folder 375)
  - Lattimore, Eleanor and Owen, 1950-1986 (Box 32, Folder 376)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1964-1970 (Box 32, Folder 377)
  - Leopold, Richard, 1952-1986 (Box 32, Folder 378)
  - Lerner, Gerda, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 379)
  - Leuchtenburg, William E., 1959-1982 (Box 32, Folder 380)
  - Levy, Eugene, 1963-1973 (Box 32, Folder 381)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 29
  - Library of Congress, 1937-1998 (Box 32, Folder 382)
  - Life Magazine, 1956-1971 (Box 32, Folder 383)
  - Limerick, Patricia Nelson, 1981-1992 (Box 32, Folder 384)
  - Link, Arthur S., 1952-1983 (Box 32, Folder 385)
  - Little, Brown, and Company, 1948-1982, undated (Box 32, Folder 386 - 387)
  - Looker, Antonina ("Nina"), 1959-1976 (Box 32, Folder 388)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 407
  - Looker, Reginald Earle, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 389)
  - Lorentz, Pare, 1952-1955 (Box 32, Folder 390)
  - Louisiana State University [general], 1941-1960 (Box 32, Folder 391)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1947-1996, undated (Box 33, Folder 392 - 395)
  - Lumpkin, Katharine DuPre, 1956-1971 (Box 33, Folder 396)
  - Lynd, Staughton, 1967-1969, undated (Box 33, Folder 397)
  - M (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 33, Folder 398 - 399)
  - M (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 34, Folder 400 - 406)
  - Macdonald, Antonina ("Nina"), 1937-1939 (Box 35, Folder 407)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1950-1968 (Box 35, Folder 408)
  - Maclachlan, Emily White, 1938-1966, undated (Box 35, Folder 409)
  - Maclachlan, John, 1938-1941, undated (Box 35, Folder 410)
  - Macmillan Company, 1937-1970, undated (Box 35, Folder 411)
  - Maier, Pauline, 1983-1997 (Box 35, Folder 412)
  - Malone, Dumas, 1949-1985 (Box 35, Folder 413)
  - Mandelbaum, Maurice, 1959-1982, undated (Box 35, Folder 414)
  - Martin, Boulware [Arkansas friend], 1926-1990, undated (Box 35, Folder 415)
  - McFeely, Mary and William S., 1963-1996, undated (Box 35, Folder 416)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 33
  - McGerr, Michael, 1982-1998 (Box 35, Folder 417)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1953-1970 (Box 35, Folder 418)
  - McGuire, William, 1953-1975 (Box 35, Folder 419)
  - McKitrick, Eric, 1954-1993 (Box 35, Folder 420)
  - McPherson, James M., 1960-1998, undated (Box 36, Folder 421 - 423)
  - Meier, August, 1941-1981 (Box 36, Folder 424)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1948 (Box 36, Folder 425)
  - Meriwether, James B., 1974-1985 (Box 36, Folder 426)
  - Michigan State University, 1958-1997 (Box 36, Folder 427)
  - Miller, William Lee, 1973-1980, undated (Box 36, Folder 428)
  - Mintz, Sidney W., 1962-1969, undated (Box 36, Folder 429)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1951-1964 (Box 36, Folder 430)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 481
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Review [title changed to Journal of American History ], 1947-1964 (Box 36, Folder 431)
  - Mitchell, Broadus, 1940-1981 (Box 36, Folder 432)
  - Miura, Susumu, 1966-1969 (Box 36, Folder 433)
  - Mondadori Publishing Co., Inc., 1966-1975 (Box 36, Folder 434)
  - Montana State University, 1956-1962 (Box 36, Folder 435)
  - Morgan, Edmund S., 1950-1996, undated (Box 36, Folder 436)
  - Morris, Willie, 1966, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 437)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1926-2000, n.d. Folder 283
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1961-1977 (Box 36, Folder 438)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1968-1989 (Box 36, Folder 439)
  - Muhlenfeld, Elisabeth, 1975-1997 (Box 37, Folder 440)
  - Murray, Pauli, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 441)
  - N (general), 1938-1997, undated (Box 37, Folder 442 - 445)
  - Nagata, Toyo Omi, 1962-1975 (Box 37, Folder 446)
  - The Nation, 1940-1965 (Box 37, Folder 447)
  - National Archives, 1947-1958, 1975, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 448)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1953-1987 (Box 37, Folder 449)
    See also: Series III. Subjects, 1947-1997 Folder 39
  - National Book Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 37, Folder 450)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1969-1991 (Box 37, Folder 451)
  - National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, 1966-1971 (Box 37, Folder 452)
  - National Humanities Center, 1978-1996 (Box 37, Folder 453)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1954-1978 (Box 37, Folder 454)
  - Neumann, William L., 1950-1970 (Box 38, Folder 455)
  - The New Republic, 1938-1992, undated (Box 38, Folder 456)
  - New School for Social Research, 1939-1940; 1961-1962 (Box 38, Folder 457)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1953-1965 (Box 38, Folder 458)
  - New York Review of Books, 1963-1998 (Box 38, Folder 459)
  - New York Times, 1961-1993, undated (Box 38, Folder 460)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1954-1983 (Box 38, Folder 461)
  - New York University, 1958-1971 (Box 38, Folder 462)
  - Nicholas, Herbert G., 1954-1992, undated (Box 38, Folder 463 - 464)
  - Nichols, Jeannette P., 1956-1964 (Box 38, Folder 465)
  - Nicklason, Fred, 1965-1970 (Box 38, Folder 466)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 35
  - North Carolina State University, 1965-1971 (Box 38, Folder 467)
  - Northern Illinois University, 1960-1969 (Box 39, Folder 468)
  - Northwestern University [includes general correspondence and Northwestern University Press], 1954-1977 (Box 39, Folder 469)
  - Norton, W.W. and Company, Inc., 1948-1993 (Box 39, Folder 470)
  - Nugent, Walter T. K., 1961-1977 (Box 39, Folder 471)
  - O (general), 1938-1998, undated (Box 39, Folder 472 - 473)
  - O'Brien, Michael, 1972-1998 (Box 39, Folder 474)
  - Odum, Howard W., 1938-1940 (Box 39, Folder 475)
  - Ohio State University, 1956-1980 (Box 39, Folder 476)
  - Olsen, Otto, 1954-1982, undated (Box 39, Folder 477 - 479)
  - Oney, Steve, 1987-1999 (Box 40, Folder 480)
  - Organization of American Historians, 1965-1994, undated (Box 40, Folder 481)
  - Oxford University
    - General, 1956-1979 (Box 40, Folder 482)
    - Harmsworth professorship, 1953-1959, undated (Box 40, Folder 483)
  - Oxford University Press
    - General, 1954-1995 (Box 40, Folder 484 - 486)
    - Oxford History of the United States, 1956-1999, undated (Box 41, Folder 487 - 494)
    - Oxford History of the United States, 1956-1999, undated (Box 42, Folder 495 - 499)
  - P (general), 1938-1999, undated (Box 43, Folder 500 - 504)
  - Palmer, Robert R., 1955-1970 (Box 43, Folder 505)
  - Pantheon Books, 1964-1985 (Box 43, Folder 506)
  - Partington, Paul G., 1976-1989, undated (Box 43, Folder 507)
  - Partisan Review, 1968-1998 (Box 43, Folder 508)
  - Patterson, Hugh M., 1962-1979 (Box 43, Folder 509)
  - Pelling, Henry M., 1954-1969 (Box 43, Folder 510)
  - Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, 1953-1958 (Box 43, Folder 511)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1949-1969 (Box 43, Folder 512)
  - Percy, Walker [includes correspondence with Bertram Wyatt-Brown and Percy relatives], 1982-1990 (Box 43, Folder 513)
  - Phi Alpha Theta, 1952-1967 (Box 44, Folder 514)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1951-1982 (Box 44, Folder 515)
  - Pierson, George W., 1958-1992 (Box 44, Folder 516)
  - Pole, Jack, 1954-1997, undated (Box 44, Folder 517)
  - Pollack, Norman, 1962-1992 (Box 44, Folder 518)
  - Pope, Robert Dean, 1968-1970 (Box 44, Folder 519)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 37
  - Potter, David M., 1948-1969, undated (Box 44, Folder 520 - 521)
  - Powell, Lawrence N., 1979-1998 (Box 44, Folder 522)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 38
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1956-1979 (Box 44, Folder 523)
  - Princeton University [general], 1950-1996 (Box 44, Folder 524 - 525)
  - Princeton University Press, 1950-1996 (Box 45, Folder 526)
  - Pulitzer Prize Committee, 1956-1999 (Box 45, Folder 527 - 528)
  - Purdue University, 1958-1969 (Box 45, Folder 529)
  - Pyle, Kenneth B., 1959-1964, undated (Box 45, Folder 530)
  - Q (general), 1938-1998, undated (Box 45, Folder 531)
  - Quadrangle Books, 1964-1972 (Box 45, Folder 532)
  - Quint, Howard, 1955-1963 (Box 45, Folder 533)
  - R (general), 1931-1995, undated (Box 46, Folder 534 - 538)
  - Rabinowitz, Howard N., 1976-1997 (Box 46, Folder 539)
  - Rainey, Glenn, 1938-1979, undated (Box 46, Folder 540)
  - Rand McNally and Company, 1955-1965 (Box 46, Folder 541)
  - Randolph, A. Philip [includes A. Philip Randolph Institute], 1965-1975 (Box 46, Folder 542)
  - Random House, Inc., 1953-1983 (Box 46, Folder 543)
  - Rankin, Jeannette, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 544)
  - Reader's Digest, 1953-1966 (Box 47, Folder 545)
  - Redkey, Edwin S., 1968-1977 (Box 47, Folder 546)
    See also: Series V. Yale University, 1944-1994 Folder 39
  - Reeve, Helen [cover letter for packet of cards and letters to Woodward during his illness in December 1999, and cards and letters to Reeve after Woodward's death], 1999-2000 (Box 47, Folder 547)
  - The Reporter, 1961-1965, undated (Box 47, Folder 548)
  - Rice University, 1959-1981 (Box 47, Folder 549)
  - Riesman, David, 1954-1981 (Box 47, Folder 550 - 551)
  - Rinehart and Co., Inc., Publishers, 1953-1958 (Box 47, Folder 552)
  - Robinson, Armstead L., 1969-1988, undated (Box 47, Folder 553)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1981 (Box 47, Folder 554)
  - Rodham, Hillary, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 555)
  - Roper, John Herbert (Jack), 1977-1999, undated (Box 47, Folder 556)
  - Rose, Willie Lee, 1959-1982, undated (Box 47, Folder 557 - 558)
  - Rosenberg, John, 1964-1998 (Box 48, Folder 559)
  - Rosengarten, Theodore [cover letter with essay on Woodward], 1998 (Box 48, Folder 560)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., 1961-1989 (Box 48, Folder 561)
  - Rubin, Louis D., Jr., 1951-1998, undated (Box 48, Folder 562 - 563)
  - Ruchames, Louis, 1961-1969 (Box 48, Folder 564)
  - Rutgers University [includes general correspondence and Rutgers University Press], 1952-1987 (Box 48, Folder 565)